Elihu Vedder
Archives of American Art, Smithsonian Institution
Elihu Vedder papers
1804-1969 (bulk 1840-1923)
Archives of American Art, Smithsonian Institution
Vedder, Elihu
9.0 linear feet
The papers of painter and illustrator Elihu Vedder measure approximately 9.0 linear feet and date from 1804-1969, with the bulk of the material dating from 1840-1923. The collection documents Vedder's personal life and work. Best known for his illustrations of the 1884 edition of The Rubaiyat of Omar Khayyam, Vedder's papers include correspondence, writings, diaries, photographs, a limited number of drawings, books and printed material, legal and financial papers, and scattered personal and family papers.
Provenance
The bulk of the collection was donated in 1962-1964 by Lawrence Fleischman and Harold Love (who bought the papers in 1926 from Mrs. Nadia Tomassi, a Vedder family friend who had held the papers since Vedder's death in 1923). Several books were donated by Irving Burton in 1964 and 1977. Some correspondence, writings, notes, and printed material were donated in 1981 by Mrs. John Breck.
Separated Material
Four originals drawings (filmed on Reel 671: 608-610 and 612) were returned to the donor and are not described in the Container Listing.
Related Material
Related material found in the Archives of American Art includes 3 letters written by Elihu Vedder that comprise a small collection donated by Charles E. Feinberg.
Alternative Forms Available
The microfilm of this collection was digitized in 2007 and original photographs were digitized in 2009. Digitized materials are available via the Archives of American Art website.
Restrictions on Access
The bulk of this collection has been digitized. Use of material not digitized requires an appointment.
Biographical Note
Elihu Vedder was born in New York in 1836. He grew up in Cuba, where his father worked as a dentist, and on his grandfather's farm in Brooklyn. He was educated in boarding schools and by tutors, and showed an interest in drawing at an early age. He began his formal training with T. H. Matteson in New York, and went on to study with Francois-Edouard Picot in Paris and Raffaello Bonaiuti in Florence.
After studying in Europe for several years, Vedder returned to the U.S. in 1860 and settled in New York, where he worked as a commercial illustrator during the Civil War. In 1864, he was one of the artists who illustrated the first American edition of Tennyson's Enoch Arden, which was published by Ticknor and Fields. During this time, he became associated with a bohemian group of artists and writers that regularly met at Pfaff's coffee shop. Some of the earliest exhibitions of his work took place at the annual spring exhibits at the National Academy of Design from 1863 to 1865. He became a member of the American Academy of Arts and Letters in 1865. After the war he returned to Europe, eventually settling permanently in Italy.
In 1869 Vedder married Elizabeth Caroline Beach Rosekrans (Carrie). They lived in Rome, where Vedder earned his living by undertaking commissioned work (what he termed "duty painting") while also producing paintings on original themes and subjects, such as The Cumaean Sibyl (1875-1878) which became one of his most celebrated paintings. Vedder's wife aided him in his work by cultivating patrons and carrying out all the business correspondence. Over the years he exhibited his work in London, Paris, New York and Boston (where it was especially well-received). While achieving a certain degree of success, he struggled throughout his career to make a living as an artist.
Vedder also carried out work on commission, designing covers for Century Magazine in 1881 and illustrations for various other publications such as Harper's. He experimented in other decorative arts also, designing glass ringwork, firebacks, and tiles; apart from some commissions for glass work from Tiffany's, these other projects never really got off the ground.
Vedder made his biggest contribution to American commercial art in 1884 with his illustrations of The Rubaiyat of Omar Khayyam. Exhibitions of the original drawings followed, which were well-attended by the public; he also painted and sold several pictures from the Rubaiyat drawings. In the 1890s he undertook several mural projects, including ones for the Walker Art Building at Bowdoin College and the Library of Congress.
In the early 1900s, Vedder built a villa on the island of Capri, where he spent the summers and falls while continuing to live the rest of the year in Rome. From this point on, he didn't undertake any new major paintings, but instead turned to writing and illustrating books of autobiography and verse. His books include The Digressions of V (1910), Miscellaneous Moods (1915), and Doubt and Other Things (1922).
Vedder died on January 29, 1923, at the age of 87.
This biographical note draws from Regina Soria's biography, Elihu Vedder: American Visionary Artist in Rome (Rutherford: Fairleigh Dickinson University Press, 1970).
Scope and Content Note
The Elihu Vedder papers measure approximately 9 linear feet and date from 1804 to 1969, with the bulk of the material dating from 1840 to 1923. The collection documents the life and work of the painter and illustrator, who was perhaps best known for his illustrations of the 1884 edition of The Rubaiyat of Omar Khayyam. Papers include correspondence, writings, diaires, photographs, a limited number of drawings, books and printed material, legal and financial papers, and scattered personal and family papers.
Correspondence consists of incoming and drafts of outgoing letters concerning both personal and professional matters. The majority of the business correspondence was written by Vedder's wife, Caroline R. Vedder, on his behalf and documents the sale and exhibition of Vedder's work, commissions for paintings, and his illustrations for books. Also found is corresondence between and amongst various members of Vedder's immediate and extended family (including early letters between his parents, Elizabeth and Elihu Vedder, Sr.), and between Caroline R. Vedder and her immediate family (including her mother, sisters, and nieces).
Writings consist of drafts, manuscripts, typescripts, and illustrations for various books that Vedder wrote late in his career after he had stopped painting, and for various other poems, essays, and stories, as well as some writings by others. Also found are several diaries belonging to Vedder and Caroline R. Vedder, which record some of the daily activities and travels of Vedder and his wife. Photographs include ones of Vedder, his studio, his friends and family, and his artwork, as well as ones of various residences, from various trips, and of an unidentified exhibition of Vedder's work. Drawings include a study for "The Rubaiyat" and "The Artist's Daughter," along with scattered sketches, plans, and bookplates. Also found are copies of Vedder's published books, and clippings, catalogs, art reproductions, and other printed material.
Also in the collection are scattered legal papers (wills, deeds, and agreements of various family members), finanical papers (such as receipts and statements), notes on family history and other family papers, miscellaney, and numerous annotated envelopes and enclosures that once housed some of Vedder's papers.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged as seven series:
Series 1: Miscellaneous Personal Papers, 1811-1938 (Boxes 1, 10; 1.0 linear foot)
Series 2: Correspondence, 1804-1951 (Boxes 2-5; 3.6 linear feet)
Series 3: Diaries, 1878-1890 (Box 5; 0.1 linear feet)
Series 4: Writings, 1848-1923, 1969 (Boxes 5-7, 10; 1.7 linear feet)
Series 5: Books and Printed Material, 1864-1939 (Boxes 7-8; 0.9 linear feet)
Series 6: Drawings, 1888-1912 (Box 8, OV 12; 0.2 linear feet)
Series 7: Photographs, 1840s-1920s (Boxes 8-9, 11, OV 13; 1.5 linear feet)
Names and Subject Terms
This collection is indexed in the online catalog of the Archives of American Art under the following terms:
Subjects-Topical:
Artists' Writings; Painting, Modern --19th century -- Italy -- Rome; Painters -- Italy -- Rome; Illustrators -- Italy -- Rome
Types of Materials:
Works of art; Diaries; Photographs
Names:
Vedder, Caroline Rosenkrans
Series Descriptions/Container Listing
- Miscellaneous Personal Papers, 1811-1938, Series 1:; (Boxes 1, 10; 1.0 linear foot)
  This series consists of miscellaneous personal and family papers, including notes on the genealogy of the Vedder family, legal and financial papers, notes on the sale and disposition of Vedder's artwork, miscellany, and a significant amount of empty envelopes and enclosures that once housed some of Vedder's papers and that are annotated with notes about the former contents. Legal papers are primarily those of Vedder's extended family and consist of the last wills and testaments of various family members (including his brother and father), deeds, agreements, and insurance policies, as well as Vedder's contract with Houghton Mifflin for The Digressions of V. Also found are various folders of miscellany, consisting of invitations, notices of Vedder's election to the National Academy of Design and The Century Association, sketches and notes, programs, report cards for Enoch Vedder (his son), business and calling cards, pages from an address book, a lock of Vedder's hair, writings, maps, a tentative catalog of Vedder's papers, and other printed material. The bulk of the series is comprised of empty envelopes and enclosures, including some empty envelopes from Vedder's correspondence, which were annotated by various members of Vedder's family and by various custodians and/or users of Vedder's papers and which suggest how the papers may have been originally organized.
  - Family History Notes, 1845-1862, undated (Reel 515, Frame 759-776)
  - Family Legal Papers, 1811-1909, (1 of 2) (Reel 528, Frame 499-550)
  - Family Legal Papers, 1811-1909, (2 of 2) (Reel 528, Frame 551-610)
  - Financial Papers, Caroline R. Vedder's Notebook of Sales, 1856-1907 (Reel 528, Frame 612-649)
  - Financial Papers, Statements, 1868-1912, 1938, (1 of 2) (Reel 528, Frame 650-699)
  - Financial Papers, Statements, 1868-1912, 1938, (2 of 2) (Reel 528, Frame 700-722)
  - Financial Papers, Receipts, 1865-1910, 1938 (Reel 528, Frame 723-769)
  - Financial Papers, 1874-1915, undated, (1 of 2) (Reel 528, Frame 770-810)
  - Financial Papers, 1874-1919, undated, (2 of 2) (Reel 528, Frame 811-850)
  - Artwork Sales and Disposition Notes, 1856-1938, (1 of 4) (Reel 528, Frame 852-902)
  - Artwork Sales and Disposition Notes, 1856-1938, (2 of 4) (Reel 528, Frame 903-956)
  - Artwork Sales and Disposition Notes, 1856-1938, (3 of 4) (Reel 528, Frame 957-1001)
  - Artwork Sales and Disposition Notes, 1856-1938, (4 of 4; partially microfilmed) (Reel 528, Frame 1002-1045)
  - Miscellany, 1857-1915, undated, (1 of 3) (Reel 529, Frame 769-813)
  - Miscellany, 1857-1915, undated, (2 of 3) (Reel 529, Frame 814-856)
  - Miscellany, 1857-1915, undated, (3 of 3) (Reel 529, Frame 857-892)
  - Miscellany, undated, (2 folders) (Reel unfilmed, Frame unfilmed)
  - Annotated Envelopes and Enclosures, undated, (16 folders) (Reel unfilmed, Frame unfilmed)
  - Oversized, Miscellaneous Family Papers, Diplomas and License of Enoch H. Rosekrans (father-in-law), 1831-1867, (see Box 10) (Reel unfilmed, Frame unfilmed)
- Correspondence, 1804-1951, Series 2:; (Boxes 2-5; 3.6 linear feet)
  Series consists of Vedder's personal, professional, and family correspondence, comprised mostly of incoming letters as well as some copies or drafts of outgoing letters. Correspondents include family, friends, artists, dealers, collectors, admirers, and publishers. The bulk of the business correspondence was written by Caroline R. Vedder on behalf of her husband, including correspondence with collectors, people who commissioned work, dealers, and publishers.
  Earliest correspondence consists of letters sent and received by various members of Vedder's immediate and extended family, including his parents, Elizabeth and Elihu Vedder, Sr., his brother, Alexander V., his maternal grandparents, Alexander and Agnes Vedder, his maternal aunt, Eveline Caister, and his paternal uncles, Levi and John Vedder. Early letters document the time the family spent apart while Elihu, Sr., was living and working in Cuba and later while the boys were living with their grandparents for a time. Of particular note is an 1850 letter from Vedder to his mother expressing his interest in drawing.
  Family correspondence consists primarily of letters between and amongst Vedder, his father, and his brother (Vedder's letters to his father detail his travels in Europe from 1857 to 1860 and his first attempts to earn a living by drawing); letters between Caroline R. Vedder, her mother, sisters, and nieces; letters between Vedder and his wife when either one of them was away from home, traveling or conducting business; and letters between Caroline R. Vedder and the children: Enoch, when he was away at a school and then living in the U.S. and Anita, when she was traveling and away from home.
  Personal correspondence concerns matters such as Vedder's engagement and marriage to Caroline Rosekrans, the death and settling the estate of his brother, Alexander, his travels, including a trip up the Nile in 1889-1890, and his friendship with other artists. Professional correspondence concerns: his illustrations and engravings of his work for various books and poems, including Enoch Arden (1863) and The Rubaiyat of Omar Khayyam (1884); the exhibiiton of his work (for instance, in the Paris International Exposition of 1878; in gallery shows in Boston and New York in 1880 and in London in 1899; and at the Architectural League of New York in 1895) as well as the unsuccessful attempt to show in the Royal Academy Exhibition of 1876; the sale of his work to private individuals and commissions for work; the reproduction and copyright of his work; Vedder's published protest in the December 1878 issue of L'Art; his award of first prize in the Competition of Christmas Cards at the American Art Gallery, and the subsequent reproduction and sale of his Christmas cards; a mural project for the Chicago World's Fair in 1892; a proposed mural project for the Boston Public Library; his book The Digressions of V (1910); and various other financial and business matters.
  Also found is some posthumous correspondence sent and received by Anita Vedder, concerning gifts, sales, and exhibitions of Vedder's work.
  See Index for List of Selected Correspondents from Series 2.
  Correspondence is arranged chronologically. Undated correspondence is arranged alphabetically at the end of the series.
  Index: Selected List of Correspondents from Series 2: Correspondence
  This list does not include the names of family members. Unless otherwise noted, date entries refer to correspondence found on Reels 515-526. When correspondence can also be found on Reel 2323, it is noted with a "see" or "see also" reference after the appropriate date.
  A
  Abbott, Mrs.: 1895
  Abbott, Sam A. B: 1894
  Abbey, Edwin A.: undated (see also Reel 2323)
  Adams, Elizabeth: undated (see Reel 2323)
  Adsit, Mary J.: undated
  Advisory Committee on Art of the Paris Exhibition: 1878
  Agnew, Mary: undated
  Ainger, Alfred: 1893 (see Reel 2323)
  Aldrich, T. B.: 1875 (see Reel 2323), 1878, 1880 (see Reel 2323)
  Aldrich, Lilian: undated
  Allen, Earl Heron: 1885, 1896 (see Reel 2323)
  Allen, Fanny B.: 1893, undated
  Allen, Henry F.: undated (see Reel 2323)
  American Academy of Arts and Letters: 1922, 1935, 1937, 1938, 1947, 1949
  American Art Gallery: 1881
  American Consul, Alexandria, Egypt: 1910
  American Federation of Arts: 1930
  American Library in Paris: 1934
  Anderson, L---: 1894
  Andrea (?), J. W.: 1876
  Appleton, F. G.: 1880
  Apolloni, A.: 1898 (see Reel 2323)
  Archibald, J. W.: undated
  Architectural League of New York: 1895
  Armstrong, D. M.: 1872, 1873, 1878, 1879, undated
  Armstrong, Helen M.: 1938
  Armstrong, Helen N.: 1871, 1872, undated
  Armstrong, T.: 1892 (see Reel 2323)
  Arnold, Edwin: undated
  Arts and Crafts Exhibition Society: 1890 (see Reel 2323)
  Ashbarton, Lady: 1876
  Ashley, M. Harry: 1872
  Ashley, O. D.: 1866
  Athenaeum Club: 1863
  Atkinson, Agnes D.: undated
  Augustine Heard and Co.: 1871
  Ault, Charles H.: 1895, 1898 (see Reel 2323)
  Austin, Alys: 1885, 1886, 1887
  Avery, Sam P.: 1879, 1893
  B
  Babcock, Maltbie Davenport: undated (see Reel 2323)
  Bale, Edwin: 1884, 1885, undated
  Bale, Jake D.: undated
  Ballard, Laura: 1869
  Ballue, P. W.: 1878
  Banks, Isabella: 1871
  Barrett, S. E.: 1898, undated
  Bartlett, [Truman H.?]: 1871
  Beale, Jessie Fremont: 1898 (see Reel 2323)
  Benedict, Bessy G.: 1889, 1890, 1891, 1894
  Benedict, Frank Lee: 1882
  Benson, Arthur: 1888 (see Reel 2323)
  Benson, Eugene: 1878, 1881
  Benson, H. M.: 1880
  Bicknell, Albion H. (Bic): 1866
  Bigelow, W. B.: 1878
  Bishop, Hattie: 1893, 1894, 1895, 1898, 1905, undated
  Black, F. C.: 1865
  Blake, Franklin: 1871
  Blythe, Isabella: 1889
  Bode, William: 1912
  Booth, George: 1884
  Bossi, Enrico: 1898 (see Reel 2323)
  Boughton, G. H.: 1878
  Bourget, Mr. and Mrs. Paul: undated (see Reel 2323)
  Bradbury, K.: undated
  Braden, Robert: 1893, 1895, 1896
  Breck, George W.: 1900, 1902, undated
  Breck, Katherine: 1903
  Bretschneider, Dora: 1905
  Brewster, Anne Hampton: 1891 (see Reel 2323)
  Briggs, Allan Lindsay: 1896
  Brimmer, Martin: 1880, 1894
  Brinkerhoff, E. A.: 1910
  Brooklyn Institute of Arts and Sciences: 1938
  Brown, Alice E.: 1874
  Brown, Florinda: 1889, 1891, 1893, undated
  Bruce, W. J.: 1888, 1889
  Burrows, Elizabeth M.: 1891
  Burton, Grace Harvey: 1898 (see Reel 2323)
  Butler, George: 1881, 1882
  Butler, J. H.: 1877
  Butler, Samuel: 1877 (see Reel 2323)
  C
  California State Library, Sutro Branch: 1919
  Carnegie Institute: 1923
  Carpenter, H. Bernard: undated
  Carpenter, Horace T.: 1912
  Carter, Jesse Benedict (American Academy in Rome): 1915
  Carter, June Benedict: 1910
  Cary, William M.: 1909
  Cave, Daniel C. A.: 1893 (see Reel 2323)
  Chanix, S. Whitney: 1865
  Chanler, Amelie: 1891 (Reel 2323)
  Chapin, H. A.: 1866
  Chapin, Mrs.: 1895
  Charles Scribner's Sons: 1887, 1888, 1892
  Chase, William L.: undated
  Churchill (?), S. H.: 1919
  Clarke, S.: undated
  Clemens, S. L.: 1883 (telegram)
  Cleveland Art Association: 1895
  Clute, Henry J.: 1887
  Cochrane, Jessie: undated
  Cole, J.: 1886
  Cole, Timothy: 1914, 1915 (see Reel 2323)
  Coleman, Caryl: 1871, 1878, 1885
  Coleman, Charles: 1865, 1866, 1871, 1880, 1882, 1883, 1886, 1893, 1904, 1905, 1910, undated
  Collins, Charles: 1885, 1886, undated
  Colnaghi, Messrs.: 1876
  Conti (?), Joan: 1886 (see Reel 2323)
  Coolidge, J. Randolph: 1888, 1889
  Corcoran Gallery of Art: 1949
  Corliss, George F: 1889, 1891
  Corell, W. S.: 1897 (see Reel 2323)
  Cortissoz, Royal: 1937, 1938
  Cromwell, Anna B.: 1894
  Crook, John: 1870
  Crowninshield, Frederic: 1910 (see Reel 2323)
  Crowninshield, Helen: 1878
  Curtis, Kate De F.: 1893
  Curtis, Lois: 1894
  D
  Daly, Augustus: 1880 (see Reel 2323)
  Daniel, P. A.: 1872
  Daniels, Cora Louise: 1885
  Davies, Robert: 1892
  Davies, William: 1876, 1878
  Day, Ben: 1866, 1882, 1892, 1900, 1910
  Dean, Sarah Fairchild: 1872
  Dickinson, Lavinia: 1892 (see Reel 2323)
  Dielman, Frederick: 1898 (see Reel 2323)
  Dixey, Ellen Sturgis: undated
  Dodd, Mead and Company: 1906 (see Reel 2323)
  Dodge, Anna Sheldon: undated
  Doll and Richards: 1880, 1889, 1890, 1938
  Donaldson, Andrew B.: 1870
  Douglas, George William: 1888
  Drake, A. W.: 1884, 1894
  Draper, Ada A.: 1871, 1873
  Drexel, Mrs. M.: 1940
  Duckworth, H.T.F.: 1891 (see Reel 2323)
  Dumaresq, J. S.: 1876-1878
  Dunham, Charles A.: 1896
  Dunthorne, Robert: 1897
  Durand, Mr.: 1880
  Dwight, Theodore F.: 1892 (see Reel 2323)
  Dyer, Margaret: 1889
  Dyer, Stella M.: undated (see Reel 2323)
  D'Ysette, Contessa: 1912 (see Reel 2323)
  E
  Earle, Charles: 1872, 1878, undated
  Edwards, Amelia B.: 1872, 1873, 1875-1880, 1882-1884, 1886-1891, 1909, undated
  Ellsworth, James W.: 1892
  Ellsworth, W. W.: 1884
  Eustaphiere, Emiy: 1871
  Ewer, F. C.: 1863
  F
  Fairbanks (?), A. A.: 1872
  Fairchild, Charles: 1872, 1880
  Fairchild, Lucius: 1875
  Farr, Edward L.: 1911
  Farrell, Eva Ingersoll: undated
  Fawcett, Edgar: undated (see Reel 2323)
  Fennel, A. J.: 1875
  Ferguson, Henry A.: 1878
  Field, Kate: 1863, 1865, 1867, 1869, 1871, 1878, 1879, 1887, undated
  Filmer, John: undated
  Finney, J. N.: 1909
  Fiske, Fannie L.: 1872, undated
  Fiske, J. N.: 1876, 1877
  Fiske, Maria: 1874, 1875
  Ford, Paul Leceister: undated
  Frampton, George: 1913 (see Reel 2323)
  Francis, Fanny Long: undated
  Frank A. Munsey and Co. (Munsey's Magazine): 1894
  Frisell, A. S.: 1897
  Frisell, S. S.: 1922 (see Reel 2323)
  Frothingham, Ellen: 1871
  Fuller, James: 1866
  G
  Galton, Mary: 1886, 1889, 1890, undated
  Garrett, Mary: 1892
  Gautier, Florence: undated (see Reel 2323)
  Gifford, R. Swain (?): 1880 (see Reel 2323)
  Gilbert, Alfred: 1898 (see Reel 2323)
  Gilder, Helena de Kay: undated
  Gilder, R. W.: 1883
  Glackmore, Mary: 1871
  Glackmore, William: 1871
  Goodman, Walter: 1876
  Gottschalk, Felix: 1887, 1888, 1891, 1892
  Graham, Louise: 1867, 1871
  Graham, William: 1878, 1881-1883, 1889-1892, 1900, 1903, 1904, 1907, 1908, 1910, 1911, undated
  Grant, ----: 1877
  Gray, David: 1870, 1878, 1879 (see Reel 2323)
  Green, Josiah: 1866, undated
  Greenwood, Grace (Mrs. S. J. Lippincott): 1876
  Griswold, Casimir Clayton (Cass.): 1866, 1871, 1872, 1892-1894
  Grover, Frances: undated
  Guckin, William G. M.: 1912
  Guerry, Prosper (Prosper Guerry Studios): 1945, 1946
  Gurnee, William B.: 1872, 1878
  Gutman, Joseph: 1866, 1867, 1870, 1871, 1874, 1880, 1885, 1887-1889, undated
  H
  Haggin, Ali Ben: 1910
  Haggin, B. B.: undated
  Hall, George Henry: 1887
  Hall, J. Frederick: 1875, 1879, 1889, undated
  Hallock, Mary: 1869
  Hallowell, Anna: undated
  Hare, Augustus: undated (see Reel 2323)
  Harper and Brothers: 1882, 1885, 1886, 1888, 1890, 1896, 1907
  Harper, J. Abner: undated
  Harvey, James Clarence: 1895
  Haskell, Celia: 1878, 1883, 1885, 1886, 1889, 1892, 1894, undated
  Haskell, E. B.: 1878, 1880-1885, 1887, 1890-1894, 1902
  Hathaway, M. J.: 1878
  Hawthorne, Julian: 1892, undated (see Reel 2323)
  Head, Barclay R.: 1883
  Hearn, George: 1909
  Heath, L. B.: undated
  Helbig, Nadine: undated (see Reel 2323)
  Henderson, Isaac: 1886
  Henderson, J. W.: 1888, 1889, 1891, 1893, 1895-1901, undated
  Hendrickson, Doll and Richards: 1866
  Herkomer, Herbert: 1898 (see Reel 2323)
  Herriman, Elizabeth (Lizzie): 1862, 1872, 1873-1875, 1878-1880, 1882, 1884, 1889, 1890, undated
  Herriman, William H.: 1879, 1880, 1892, 1910
  Hess, Selmar: 1890
  Hitchcock, DeWitt C.: 1865, 1866, undated
  Hitchcock, Linda: 1865
  Holland, Alex: 1867
  Home, D. D.: 1881 (see Reel 2323)
  Hooker, J. C.: 1876
  Hooper, C.----: 1866
  Hooper, Mary: 1874
  Houghton Mifflin Company: 1890 (see Reel 2323), 1935
  How, Charles: 1871, 1872, 1874, 1875
  Howe, Mrs.: 1874
  Howells, William Dean: 1908
  Hulton, Lawrence: undated
  Hunt, Richard H.: 1892
  Hutchins, Mary Hurd: undated
  I
  Ives, E. H.: 1889
  Ives, H. Davis: 1898
  J
  J. B. Lippincott Company: 1886
  Jackson, Helen Hunt: 1880 (see Reel 2323)
  James, Olive B.: 1936
  Jarves, James J.: 1878, 1891
  Jarves, Mrs. James J.: undated
  Johnson, Laura Winthrop: 1880, 1884
  Johnson, R. N.: 1886, 1915
  Johnson, Virginia H.: 1888, undated
  K
  Kale, ----: 1878
  Keed, Caroline G.: 1895
  Keen, Ida E.: 1889
  Keene, Francis B.: 1921
  Kellogg, Mrs. Frank: 1891
  Kelly, Eugene: undated (see Reel 2323)
  Kelly, Sarita: undated (see Reel 2323)
  Kennedy, E. G. (?) (H. Wunderlich and Co.): 1886, 1892, undated
  Kingsley, Rose: 1896 (see Reel 2323)